cnduk.org 2019-05-06

# Privacy policy - Campaign for Nuclear Disarmament

The Campaign for Nuclear Disarmament (CND) is committed to protecting your privacy. This policy explains how we use any personal information we collect about you.

  * What information do we collect about you
  * How will we use the information about you?
  * Security
  * Access to your information and amending your information
  * Cookies
  * Other websites
  * Transfer of your data internationally
  * Changes to our privacy policy
  * How to contact us

**What information do we collect about you**

In general you can visit CND’s website without disclosing any personal information about yourself. There are times, however, when we may request information from you. We collect information you give to us by email,various forms on the website, over the telephone,face to face or by postal mail.

We collect information about you when you join, make a donation, become a supporter, place an order for our products, complete an online action, sign a petition, provide us with data about your campaigning interests or interact with our social media tools. Website usage information may be collected using cookies. ** **

**How will we use the information about you?**

We will send you campaigning information by email or SMS, we think may be of interest to you. We will continue to send you information by post where we have assessed there is a legitimate interest for us to do so.

CND shares data with Scottish CND and national, regional, area and local CND groups, but only in order to fulfil the aims of CND.  This enables groups to publicise CND events and information.  All CND groups follow data protection guidelines. If you would prefer to be excluded the sharing of information with other CND groups, please contact us so we can ensure your details are not shared.

We may use your information collected from the website to personalise your repeat visits to our website.

We may disclose your data to our service providers who render services to us or you on our behalf such as delivering postal mail,sending emails  and processing payments (all of which are contractually obliged to act only on our instructions and in accordance with applicable laws, including GDPR).

** ** **Security**

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect ** **

**Access to your information and amending your information**

If you would like a copy of some or all of the personal information we hold about you, please email [**enquiries@cnduk.org**](mailto:enquiries@cnduk.org) or write to us at CND, Mordechai Vanunu House, 162 Holloway Road, London, N7 8DQ. We may make a reasonable charge for this service. (eg, for repeated requests).

We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date. You may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate. We will retain some basic information to avoid sending you unwanted materials in the future and to ensure we do not duplicate information.  This is superseded by your right to erasure (“the right to be forgotten”).  Following this request all of your data will be removed from all CND systems and any financial agreements, such a Direct Debit, will be ended. ** **

**Cookies**

Cookies are text files, used by your computer’s browser, that store visitor session data. Cookies, by themselves, do not identify the individual user. Cookies are commonly used on the Internet and do not harm your system. If you want to know more about cookies please go to [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) which explains how cookies work and how you can manage their use.

We currently use cookies to collate general management data which is used to plan enhancements to our services. Some cookies are external managed e.g. GoogleAnalytics, and are covered by their own privacy policies.

CND never stores any personal information in cookies (on any computer that you may use) that can be used to identify you, such as your name or account numbers.

If you do not want us to use cookies you may be able to configure your browser not to accept them. Please refer to your browser’s ‘help’ facility for further information. However, in a few cases some of our website features may not function as a result.

**Other websites**

Our website – [www.cnduk.org](http://ww.cnduk.org/) – contains links to other websites. This privacy policy only applies to our website so when you link to other websites you should read their own privacy policies. ** **

**Transfer of your data internationally**

The DPA and GDPR restrict the transfer of data outside of the EU and EEA. Our primary web server is located in the UK, however some of the suppliers and systems that we use can be based in other countries which are outside of the EU and EEA. This may occur, for example, by using online services with servers based in other countries or which route data via such systems. CND will ensure that information which you provide is only transferred to other countries (which do not have data protection laws equal to the DPA and GDPR) provided that the organisations involved have certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield (for organisations based in the USA) or similar stringent certification to ensure that adequate safeguards are in place to protect your rights and your data. ** **

**Changes to our privacy policy**

We keep our privacy policy under regular review and will place any updates on this [webpage](https://cnduk.org/privacy-policy) . This privacy policy was reviewed and updated May 2018. ** **

**How to contact us**

Please contact us if you have any questions about our privacy policy or information we hold about you.  
By email: [ **enquiries@cnduk.org**](mailto:enquiries@cnduk.org)  
By post: CND, Mordechai Vanunu House, 162 Holloway Road, London, N7 8DQ.

© Campaign for Nuclear Disarmament, a company limited by guarantee, registered in England and Wales no. 3533653.  
Registered Office: 162 Holloway Road, London N7 8DQ. Privacy Policy. Website design by [Hands Up](https://handsup.co.uk/)
